RISHI THAPA

B/1, Vrundavan Appt, Nr, Arbudadevi Flats, Ghatlodia, Ahmedabad -380061. Gujarat +91 97277-1455 thaparishi988@gmail.com



EXECUTIVE CHEF / CULINARY ARTS PROFESSIONAL

About Me

A Skilled Culinary Professional, recognized for a comprehensive knowledge of international and National cuisine and an innovative approach to setting the stage for a customized dining experience. Over 12 years of progressive experience managing the provision of fine dining for hotels, restaurants, country clubs, and clubhouses; refining the art of cooking; developing impressive menus; and preparing culinary dishes influenced by culturally diverse regions around the globe.

Skills -

- . Menu Design / Generating new recipes/Development
- · Staffing / Training / Instructing
- · Catering / Banquets / Events
- · Dining Room / Kitchen Operations
- · Resource Procurement / Inventory
- · Conferences / Special Occasions
- · Supervision (Front / Back of House)
- · Customer Service / Guest Relations
- · Safety / Sanitation / HACCP
- \cdot Budgeting / Cost Reduction
- · Consultant Specialist

Education

Jul 2006 - May 2008 BACHELOR OF COMMERCE

SWAMINARAYAN GURU COMMERCE COLLEGE

May 2008 - Jun 2009 DIPLOMA IN FOOD AND PRODUCTION

ASIA PACIFIC INSTITUTE OF MANAGEMENT

Jun 2005 - Jul 2005 FINANCIAL ACCOUNTING SYSTEM

KRISHNA INSTITUTE

Work experience

May 2015 - Present

CORPORATE CHEF

FOOD SOLUTION (INDIA) LTD

- Product development or food innovation and test new products and supplies for food
 establishments like hotel chains and restaurants, food manufacturers and other companies
 associated with the food and beverage industry.
- Develop new products by conducting consumer testing, observing market trends and modifying recipes, administer surveys and let customers rate how they perceive sample products including sauces, soups, starters and gravies. record the flavor, portion and price that customers prefer,

- making tasty and visually appealing food products based on that.
- Find better ways to retain the flavor, freshness, consistency and nutritional content of mass-produced, packaged food products.
- I have worked in Dubai as an Ex. Chef (sales promotion) at Fathima Group of company behalf of food solution (I) Ltd. for products development.

Jun 2014 - Apr 2015

EXECUTIVE CHEF

LA CUISINE FINE DINE MULTICUISINE RESTAURANT

- Supervised the dining and service operations of chain group fine dine restaurant.
- Designed and implemented a creative menu with the use of fresh, local organic ingredients to provide a fine dining experience with high class customers.
- Provided personal chef services for residents and a variety of high class peoples.
- Coordinated and executed catering services, both on and off site for events ranging from weddings to conferences.

Dec 2011 - May 2014

F&B MANAGER & CULINARY CHEF

PRANAV JOSHI'S COOKING ACADEMY

- Supervised service operations for three different areas (Cooking class, fine dine cafe, private dine restaurant and private sky B.B.Q).
- Directed the activities of 20-25 staff, engaged in full-service restaurant operations (food preparation, customer service, chefs, cooks, assistants, and wait staff).
- Reorganized the layout of kitchens and dining areas; and developed creative, diverse menus
 incorporating the cuisine commonly associated with independent, fine dining restaurants as well as I
 took class at cooking academy and teach cooking culinary.

Apr 2007 - Nov 2011

KITCHEN MANAGER

TOMATO RESTAURANT

- Developed new ideas and put new recipes along with corporate chef.
- Supervised the floor, C.C.D out let as well as kitchen and outdoor catering.
- Handling F&B production and Service area, ensuring compliance with company standards in all
 areas of operation, including product preparation and delivery, customer relations, training and
 developments.
- Ensuring that the highest quality products and services are delivered to each customer and unique taste.

Mar 2005 - Mar 2007

F&B MANAGER

HILTON HOTEL

- Responsible for planning and directing food preparation in kitchens.
- Involves a large degree of supervising with sous chef and other staff, as well as keeping an eye out for
 problems that arise in the kitchen and seizing control of a situation at a moment's notice.
- Take care of F&B services.

Nov 2003 - Feb 2005

ASSISTANT F&B MANAGER

PALANPUR HOTEL, MOUNT ABU, RAJASHTAN

- Manage all F&B and day to day operations within budgeted guideline and to the highest standards.
- Preserve excellent levels of internal and external customer service.
- Design exceptional menus, purchase goods and continuously make necessary improvements.
- Report on management regarding sales results and productivity.

Computer Proficency

- Computer proficient in MS windows, Outlook, MS office and Internet.
- Quick-books and financial software.





Working with Pranav Joshi

Extra Curricular Activities

Achievement Recipes & interview published in some famous newspapers, magazine and TV shows.

- The times of India (Gujarat).
- Ahmedabad Mirror (Ahmadabad Edition).
- Mandi Reporter (Agra).
- Divya Bhashkar (Gujarat).
- Femina Magazine (Gujarat Edition).
- Attend Conference on "FOOD ADVICE TOPIC".
- 2 Episode of "RASIO NI RANGAT" on DD Girnar and DD National channel.
- I am working with Celebrity Chef "PRANAV JOSHI"
- I have worked with "Food Food" National Channel as an Assistant Food & production Manager in show of BUDGET KITCHEN".
- I have done "Khana Khazana kitchen Queen Competition Season-2" in T.V show as a Judge at Ahmedabad.

References

SEEVALINGUM SOOBEN

CHEF DE PARTIE OF HOTEL HILTON (MAURITIUS)

Email Id: Seevalingum. Sooben@hilton.com

Contact No: +23057098641

FAIZ SANGE/DIRECTOR OF HOSPITALITY SERVICES (DUBAI)

FAIRWAY (Catering Services L.L.C)

Email Id: faiz.sange@fairwaydubai.ae

Contact No: +971508767590

CELEBRITY CHEF PRANAV JOSHI

CHEF PRANAV JOSHI IS PASSIONATE ABOUT COOKING. HE BECAME A HOUSEHOLD NAME AFTER HIS POPULAR RASOI SHOW ON ETV GUJARATI AND FOOD-FOOD CHANNEL.

Email Id: Pranav707@hotmail.com / chefpranavjoshi@gmail.com

Contact No: +91 9825026370

Personal Details

Father Name : Veerbahadur Thapa

• Sex : Male

Date of Birth : 18th Sep 1987

Marital Status : SingleNationality : Indian

• Languages : English, Hindi, Rajasthani and Gujarati

Passport No. : J 5149861

•	Place of Issue	: Ahmedabad		
•	Date of Issue	: 03/03/2011		
•	Date of Expiry	: 02/03/2021		

• Reading, Listening to Music meets the other people who came the part of the world and share their views culture and attitude also. I try to make and learn new things in the same industry and cooking.

Hobbies